# Jesse Owusu Yeboah

# Software Engineer

#### **PROFILE**

I am a passionate frontend Engineer who has a strong background in tech. I'm dedicated to building user-friendly and visually appealing software experience. My personality drives my curiosity and problem solving skills, which I take along to any project I find myself. I aim at being counted among the best software engineers in Ghana by learning and growing in the field. My goal is to contribute my expertise to innovative projects and collaborate in a team who share my dedication to excellence.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Frontend Developer (Remote)

07/2024 - 09/2024

Ben-Meredith Consulting

- Collaborated with backend engineers and UI/UX designers to gather and analyze software requirements, effectively identifying and resolving bottlenecks in functionality implementation
- Designed and implemented user-friendly interfaces that enhanced accessibility and engagement for a diverse range of users, utilizing responsive design principles.
- Collaborated closely with team members to streamline workflows and optimize productivity.

## Frontend Developer

Innorik Ghana

10/2023 – 09/2024 Kotobabi, Spintex, Ghana

- Contributed to the migration of an ERP from VB.net ∂ to React.js which improved user experience and performance.
- Utilized Flutter for mobile application development, ensuring cross-platform compatibility and a seamless user experience.
- Implemented best practices in coding, testing, and documentation to maintain high standards of software quality.
- Optimizing and refactoring codes on the daily basis

#### Frontend Developer (Bootcamp)

Amalitech Ghana

05/2023 - 06/2023 Accra, Ghana

- Designed user-friendly interfaces and ensured seamless functionality across various platforms.
- Received daily mentorship from experienced software engineers.
- Designed and implemented a product feedback application as final project. https://todo-list-app-8l1u.vercel.app/ *⊗*

#### **Frontend Engineer**

Creative Bibini

07/2021 – 10/2022 Accra, Ghana

- Received daily mentorship from project supervisor.
- Optimized and refactored code on the daily basis .
- Created user-friendly interfaces to enhance accessibility and engagement across diverse user bases.

## **EDUCATION**

**High National Diploma** 

Accra Technical University Study: Computer Science

09/2020 – 09/2023 Accra, Ghana

# **SKILLS**

# Frameworks and

- Libraries
- React.js, Next.js
- Typescript
- Version control
- TailwindCSS
- Shadcn-ui
- Antd-ui
- Devextreme

### Languages

- Javascript
- HTML
- CSS
- Python
- C++
- Java
- PHP

# **INTERESTS**

Open-source — | Hackathon | leetcode | Great Frontend

**Tools and Platforms** 

Vercel OpenAI

• Swagger

• Postman

• Git

# **LANGUAGES**

English  $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet$  Twi